I'm Akiko Yoshida, announcer of Nippon Hoso (Japan Broadcasting Corporation), and I've been an idol fan for 30 years now.
I've been a fan of idols for 30 years, and as of this recording, this is the person who came to one of the idol events that I'm currently doing without being asked.
I'm Hana Kojima from Amefurashi, and it's nice to meet you.
Yesterday... at a live house far away called Shibuya Loftline...
The reason she became an idol is because she didn't want to come to cram school.
That's right, I'm embarrassed to say that I think everyone wants to be an idol.
I'm going to tell you the story about how I became an idol because I didn't want to study.
This is the first time I've heard this motivation.
Really? I think there are a lot of people out there.
I don't think so.
Have there ever been? I got an instructor.
Well, sure.
No, I don't have one. I'm learning.
Maybe not.
I don't want to study because my family will tell me I don't have to study if I have other things to do.
I don't want to study because my family will tell me that I don't have to study if I have other things to do.
Normally, you would tell your family that you are not that interested in learning.
But you didn't tell them that, did you?
You didn't tell them that, did you?
Yes, but at that time I told my parents that I really didn't want to study anymore.
I told my parents I didn't want to study anymore.
I told my parents that I didn't want to study anymore, and they told me to find something else that I could devote myself to.
That's what they told you.
Good story.
A little better than what I heard yesterday.
It's a little different.
I was told that.
But I ignored it.
I came up with the idea that I could quit if I got busy.
I guess I didn't get it straight from my parents.
I didn't get it at all.
So I decided to get busy and started being an idol.
That's why I became an idol.
Wearing frilly clothes and singing cute songs.
Singing cute songs
Smiling and waving.
I liked Momokuro before I joined the agency, and I went to some of her live shows.
So I know what it's like to be an idol, and I liked Momokuro-san, so I knew that if I wanted to be an idol, I wanted to be like her.
Momoguro is totally different, depending on which elements you take out.
She changed the era of idiosyncrasies. I'm sure she changed the times.
I'm not a royal idol, but...
It's what I wanted to be.
You wanted to be like that? To be like that...
It's a little bit like that... but the enthusiasm comes out of it.
And how is Kojima-san doing now?
You've become an idol with a lot of special skills.
You seem to have arrived at an idol with a lot of skills.
That's right.
I have a lot of special skills.
You know...
I started out as an idol.
Some people are in the idol agency because of their special skills.
Did you have any special skills when you started idolizing? I couldn't do anything at all. I couldn't study and I don't like sports.
You don't like sports? I don't like exercise. I don't have that image. I'm not good at it.
I'm not good at talking either. You seem to like it. You talk like someone who likes to talk.
I'm not like that now, but I used to be.
He's got a story for yesterday's event.
What's with the mimicry? He brought his championship belt.
Oh, the comedy... Oh, yes, the comedy.
I brought it again today. It's okay, it's okay.
You like to talk, don't you? I grew up like that.
You didn't like it at first?
I didn't like it at first. I didn't have any special skills at all.
But as I got into it, I wanted to try my hand at more and more things, and the number of things I tried increased.
But you said that being an idol is about having people see you as gay.
Yes, the more gay people there are, the better.
So today, you already have something gay, don't you?
I did.
So you're not using this today?
Why not?
I prepared it precisely.
I knew you'd say that.
Please let me try it.
Let's see what you can do.
What do you have to show us?
As for what you've prepared...
I'm an impersonator.
Yes, yes, yes, yes. I do a lot.
Every day.
If you search the hashtag "Kojimana's daily impersonations" on Twitter.
There are about 500 impersonations.
I'd like to introduce some of them to you.
Oh! You mean the ones that were originally selected?
Yes, the original selection.
I thought the quality was good.
Yes! If you could show it to us...
I'm not doing a mimic, but...
I'm trying to do my own style of mimicry.
First of all, I did this Mahjong imitation.
A mahjong impersonation?
I've been wanting to do a mahjong pai imitation for a while.
So that's what this is about.
This is...
It's all me.
Right?
Yes.
Not only the so-called self-worship, but also the creation.
Yes, it's all me.
Right?
Yes.
What's more...What's more...
It's pretty expensive.
That exhibition fee is already on the table.
Yes, sir.
And it's in good shape.
I made sure it's in good condition.
I'm sorry... this has quite an impact.
It's not the kind of thing idols do on their first try, is it?
I don't know...
It's the kind of thing idols do in the fourth level or so.
Really?
It's my favorite too.
I can see why.
I mean, don't your fans like things with strong flavors too much?
That's right.
Kojima-san's fans are usually like that.
When you do an impersonation or something like that, they're just like, "Oh, well, he's going to do it, right?
My fans would probably just go along with the normal flow of things.
I heard that you can't win unless you can come up with something like this.
The next time you do this, you'll be taking the high road, and you know it's not the high road.
I know it's not the most popular one, but I think it's a little bit special.
I did this imitation... this imitation... what a cosplay...
It's not cosplay... but where's the difference between cosplay and a thing... it's totally different... the house is already prepared, you know...
The spray is to make the character look like the character, like buying a bagger or something and showing it to yourself and taking pictures of yourself.
For me, the difference between cosplay and impersonation is that with impersonation, the goal is to do the best you can with what you have at home, and that's what I did.
I made it all from things I had at home, and the sunglasses were just right.
Yes, I found the perfect ones, and I made these gloves, not ski gloves, but gloves for skiing.
Oh, they're huge! Yes, they are.
These are the gloves I used to wear for Halloween when I dressed up as a character from "Kaze no Tani no Nearest Neighbor".
The most recent gloves? Yes, I used my most recent gloves, but I had ski wear.
And I had enough hair from Nick's to make it long.
It was more interesting to listen to the process of how it was done.
Do you do this kind of work? Yes, this is a very classic imitation. This is not all, is it?
There's more. Do you know Yokohama Tire?
Yokohama Tire, you know, the tire company with the logo?
You see their logo on billboards? What do you mean?
Change the nose from this side to that side. It's a nice change.
The lip of Yokohama Tire has a strong lip. Yes, his eyes are strong and you can't see them if they were transparent.
This is not an imitation but an icon. No, it's not. I took this picture to look like Yokohama Tire's face.
The idol side is saying it's a copycat, so it's not.
This is a great idea. Did you come up with this yourself? This is amazing... it just so happens to be a request from a fan.
Yokohama Tire was requested by a fan. Yes, I came up with the other ones, but this one was a fan's request.
Fan's request Are your fans only broadcasters?
They're all a little quick-witted, and it'd be fun to do Yokohama Tire, I think it'd be a hit.
I think it's a hit project. But it's a good one. The last one? Not the last. Not the last? It's not the last. - Not the last?
By the way, do you know what this next impersonation is?
A big dog sleeping on a sofa?
Not at all. Think a little softer.
The red socks are real.
Fried shrimp.
That's right! That's right!
It's an impersonation of a fried shrimp!
I don't know why I feel so fulfilled, but I don't know why I don't feel fulfilled.
Isn't it amazing?
This is a blanket that has been in Kojima prefecture for a long time, but it's brown.
I didn't want to show my face without makeup, but I wanted to do an impersonation.
So I looked at the blanket for a while.
I thought, "This is the batter for fried prawns.
Were there red socks?
Yes, I did.
Your family must be a little surprised.
I thought Hara-chan was doing something.
I asked her to help me take a picture of this, too.
But I didn't tell him what I was going to imitate.
I started by asking her what she was doing.
But when I tell them it's fried shrimp, they give me a standing ovation.
They give me a standing ovation.
We have an environment that nurtures talent, don't we?
Like what you said earlier about finding something you're passionate about.
Kojima Prefecture is a great place to nurture talent like that.
The last one was a magazine impersonation.
I tried to imitate a fixed sentence.
These magazine impersonations have become a series.
Wait a minute... this is an imitation?
Isn't this the one they sell at Jimbo's?
It's exactly the same.
There's one from the 80's that's exactly like that.
That's what I was trying to achieve.
Is all this Kojima-san's?
Yes, it's all me.
I'm already getting into the breath of performance art.
I edited all these comments myself.
You made them?
I edit all my impersonations.
I write a lot of nonsense.
Like the Ameflasi feature.
Amefurashi wouldn't be featured in a mediocre magazine.
It doesn't exist yet. It's a different era.
It's very different.
It's an impossible feature.
But we do that kind of thing.
I'd like to talk about the Staples Festival.
That's right.
I was going to do that.
But there's a theme behind the festival.
It's called "Geisha Fest".
That's right.
We had a nickname for it.
Each idol has his or her own characteristics
Each of them has their own specialties.
Each of us is good at what he/she is good at.I thought I'd let the people who are good at what they do play to their strengths.
I thought I'd have them compete in what they're good at.
Mr. Kojima was on the stage a lot, wasn't he?
No, I wasn't.
There are four of us in the group.
I got three.
In a group of four, there are those who get two and those who get three.
But...
But the monobokeira last sword ball
They were all high quality.
Oh, by the way...
Well, thank you very much.
I'm glad to hear that.
Of all the idols in Staples, you have a unique image of what it means to be an idol.
You have a very unique image of idols, don't you?
I don't think so.
I think I'm just a regular idol.
Is there anyone who wants to do this with me?
Let's make something ordinary.
I don't think so.
I haven't found anyone yet.
Do you enjoy what you do?
Yes, it's fun.
To imitate something like this.
It's fun to think about what I'm going to do when I'm walking around.
It's also fun to think about what I'm going to do when I'm walking around.
That's a talent.
Really?
That makes me happy.
It's a talent.
But at the moment, I'm just an idol.
I'm not sure if it's right for me.
But lately I've been wondering the same thing.
You're late.
Lately?
Recently.
What do you mean by recently?
I've been going for a boyish look lately.
That's one of the things that makes you stand out from all the other staples.
That's right.
Even at that point, I thought I was out of the mainstream idol style.
In a way, boyish idols have always been a part of history.
In a sense, boyish idols have always been a part of history, and there has always been someone in the entertainment industry.
I think it's a royal road in a sense that it's not wrong.
That's true, but...
But recently, there are more and more comedians who do comedy or mimicry.
I've been seeing more and more comedies like that.
I don't know when it happened.
I'm a little worried that you're trying to become a comedy idol.
I'm a little concerned.
I'm worried about this too.
I'm worried about this, too," I said with a grin.
I'm extremely anxious.
I think you're enjoying it.
I'm not sure what I'm going to do.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
That's the sound of someone who's totally plotting.
"What am I going to do?
I'm wondering what I'm going to do.
I'll show you what Kojima-san was thinking about at the StarPlaza festival.
I'd like you to tell me what you were thinking
In the next video, I'd like to hear some of your thoughts in a documentary-like manner.
I'll do my best.
I'm serious.